JAMES SKOMSKY

Phoenixville, PA 19460

Phone: (484) 901-6678 | Email: James.Skomsky@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/James-Skomsky/ | GitHub: https://github.com/skomja00

Home Page: http://cis-linux2.temple.edu

SUMMARY

SQL Developer with 10+ years professional experience in DDL/DML, development standards, and data delivery operational services. Additional industry experience with object oriented scripting and programming using Ruby On Rails as well as C#. Proven development skills creating and optimizing SQL procedures in both OLTP and OLAP instances. Experience using BCP and SQL transactions to import data from various data sources. Takes initiative and uses all opportunities to develop and broaden skills. Successful collaboration in-person and hybrid settings on diverse and outsourced teams as well as self-directed efforts.

SKILLS

Languages: SQL | HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript ES6 | JSP and Java | ASP.NET and C# | Ruby

Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals Certificate H582-1131 Data Format Standards: JSON, XML, YAML, ISO HL7, ANSI X12

HTTP communication protocols RESTful APIs | .NET Core Web APIs | SOAP Web Services

Soft Skills: Azure DevOps | GIT | Agile Scrum | Test Driven Development | Project Documentation | SDLC | Data

Mapping | Jira Kanban | 24x7 Support | Requirements Gathering

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Webstaurant Store Inc. | Lititz, PA

2021-present

Database Developer

Ultimately responsible for performance of all database requests from application development teams. Assist with day-to-day operations including DML requests, query performance investigations, automated job failures and data investigation. Participate on projects for the database development organization applying my strong knowledge and experience of Microsoft SQL Server primarily version 2016 to make complex database processes run more efficiently.

- o Complete Product Backlog Items (PBIs) for the DBA team using Azure DevOps Boards.
- o Create Pull Requests in Microsoft Visual Studio Community 2019 to commit code for Peer Review.
- o Merge approved code to MSSQL Server projects to Azure DevOps Repos for production deployment
- o Analyze SQL Execution Plans to tune the performance of queries using Solarwinds SentryOne Plan Explorer.
- o Develop, optimize and implement stored procedures and functions using T-SQL.
- o Ensure compliance of standards and conventions for database development.
- o Resolve urgent requests affecting online orders, PCI compliance, & other similar issues.
- o Test code updates against RedGate database clones to ensure successful PROD deployments.
- o Participate in multiple Agile Scrum teams including daily standups, effort planning, sizing, and retrospectives.
- o Develop, implement and support automated processes used to for data processing and data transfers

Cerner Health Services Inc. | Malvern. PA

2015-2019

Senior Software Engineer

Developed MS SQL stored procedures and ETL frameworks to automate data delivery for large-scale Financial Data Warehouse. Document Management migration projects developed with Ruby programming. ASP.NET C# coding for production XML data sources.

- o Streamlined X12 837/835 data integration and messaging for Onbase® by Hyland payment and remittance clearing house ensuring payments and balances were accurately reflected and up to the minute
- o ASP.NET C# LINQ to XML coding improvements/fixes for Summa Health: Akron Hospital System
- o Developed SQL BCP process to monitor payer modifications of SSI Group Pre-Billing Eligibility Edits
- o Maintained customer support ticket queue using BMC Remedy Service Management system
- o 24x7 after-hours on call support identifying and resolving IT emergencies using (x)matters® alert system

Siemens Medical Solutions | Malvern

2000-2015

Systems integration and stored procedure development for the Soarian Provider Accounting application

- o Created SQL Stored Procedures to Extract and Transform data to many foreign receiving vendor specifications for dozens of clients. Used SFTP protocols to transfer the data to be used by the vendor.
- o Interfaced population health management Core Measures data for multiple cohorts per Centers for Medicare & Medicaid Services (CMS) requirements for the entire Soarian client base.
- o Led ETL project to streamline claim billing accuracy and A/R reduction of 3M™ Ambulatory Revenue Management application for T.J. Samson Community Hospital
- o Full SDLC development of HIPAA Security Log data integration for FairWarning® and P2Sentinel™ clients.

Shared Medical Systems | Malvern

1995-2000

Senior Programmer

- o HL7 interface development, installation, testing and maintenance
- o Conducted full life cycle SDLC in multiple software environments including mainframebased Invision Patient Management/Patient Accounting, Signature and client-server based Soarian Financials
- o Developed model interface from Provider Accounting to Physician Group applications

EDUCATION

Temple University - Web Development Continuing Studies - College of Science and Technology Rutgers University - Bachelor of Arts – Computer Science Major and Accounting Minor

USER GROUPS

Philly SQL Server User Group - Attend monthly educational events, workshops and networking opportunities to increase skills and knowledge of latest industry insight from Database Professionals.